okay so I already covered why together
Tec is in my opinion better than
open-source even though we were course
gonna use open source so I'm doing the
same now for blockchain so what makes us
different than blockchain and better
than blockchain light open-source is
because we were gonna use blockchain
when we need to when it makes sense to
do so but the pitfalls they have the
people don't understand it and people
don't trust the product that came from
it even if it is more trustworthy that's
why it's there when we create it
together and therefore there are tools
to be able to say I don't understand
that I needed to understand that and
enough trust in the whole that we can
somewhat pass off our sense making a
people who do understand it to say okay
I know that this is being done out in
the open for all of the tech people to
see so though my brain doesn't
comprehend fully what what blockchain is
enough people who do are involved and I
can say I don't understand that I really
want to understand that a lot of what
for blockchain is that although it is
more powerful it still has to compete in
marketplace
with all of the technology that already
has all the people and already has the
trust because it was built up even if
it's a roadie in the trust that erosion
of trust is eroding it for them to
people within the blockchain space trust
it because they understand what it is
but the people outside it don't trust it
the people who don't understand what it
is don't understand why I should trust a
blockchain more than I would trust
Google when I can't trust Google more
than I would trust Facebook when I can't
trust Facebook at least there's
something I can I can point to I can
point to Zuckerberg I can point to who
owns it and sew them eroding trust
erodes it for the rest when as it's not
done together and the more we the bigger
the together is that we do it with and
for the more powerful it is and the less
risky it is and so blockchain does does
amazing stuff but like with a smaller
group of people it's not the blockchain
is transparent but how you get and how
you get there's transparent enough for
the techies but it's not transparent
enough for the rest of us it's not like
we're like live on YouTube working
through what we need to work through
so that is available for every member
that comes down the line are they gonna
watch it nope but because they could
there's there's a trust built there that
we're not asking people and that like
we're looking for tools of what don't
you trust and how do you trust it or
whatever the system is we start with it
can always be improved and part of what
they do in the block and all the
individual projects and then the bigger
overarching projects like holo chain are
that they have like their protocol right
there following that's literally what
they are but you can't leave Otani on
making the protocol better not as a end
user right so having it be that like
there are systems to make it viable for
non techie people everyday people to say
what's working and what's not working
and be empowered to make it better
is why a technology company that we all
own and operate together is so needed
because it's both more powerful the more
that together is if it's you know a
thousand of us we can create a certain
thing if weeds million of us we can
create something fits billions of us we
can create a world that works for
everybody and so that isn't what they
offer they offer decentralization
because we need it we need to be able to
have trust we do people have our
information and have access to it
ourselves and be able to know people are
trustworthy we need that piece of it but
the system of creating it isn't giving
everyday people trust in it how we are
going to create which is democratically
transparently and for diversity so that
everything can be improved because the
democracy piece that is broken in the
world that you can't you can't vote with
your feet I can't just leave Canada if I
don't like my Prime Minister you
absolutely can leave together attack if
you don't like we don't want you to
because you're gonna dissipate the
energy so we're gonna make it work for
you as much as possible without giving
up our sovereignty right if you need me
to go vegan or not go vegan no if you
are offering solutions for vegans and
non-vegans and you can be either one of
those then why would you leave to start
a vegan project you might because really
don't want like what isn't working for
you here and can we make it
and if we can make it work we're gonna
make it work because we don't want them
to vote with their feet and leave and
dissipate the energy that's what
diversity is creating for diversity and
transparently is like if it's not
transparent enough for you to trust it
what do we need to do
I'm not installing cameras in my in my
house
we are meeting live on camera for an
hour that's basically the only time we
communicate there's a tiny bit of
communication elsewise it's like setting
that up like hey read this thing do this
but most of our internet interactions
are that are like transparently live
online so that we can work through
issues and as issues arise find systems
to deal with them in increasing numbers
so figuring out what does together look
like what does creating technology look
like together and how do we improve that
system how do we improve the product and
so together tech creating a tech
cooperative is powerful and less risky
and now that I've been talking about
that for years my next video is gonna be
how we're actually not a technology
cooperative thank you